Jason Xavier

Email: jasxavier7@gmail.com

Mobile: (+64) 21 298 8384

Address: Waitakere City, Auckland

Portfolio:

https://portfolio-jxav22.vercel.app/

GitHub:

https://github.com/jxav22

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jason-xavier-36b938218/

Career Objective

I would like to be involved in **full-stack development**, as I love coding and would be eager to develop a wide range of skills.

I am a fan of everything to do with problem-solving and innovation and I strongly appreciate clean, elegant, workable solutions. In line with this, I like working collaboratively and sharing knowledge and skills to explore different ideas.

Skills Summary

Documentation

I have always placed a strong emphasis on writing readable, workable code. My focus on this allowed me to resurrect old projects and upgrade them with the knowledge that I gained from my degree. An example of this is my Snake program. I used my knowledge of **algorithm design**, **OOP**, and **SOLID** principles to evolve it into a modular, reusable, and resource efficient design which I have successfully implemented in both **JavaScript** and **C**.

Team work & Communication

I put extra effort into cultivating my teamwork and interpersonal skills. To this end, I try to get involved in as many growth-inducing activities as I can.

I attend toastmaster sessions to develop my communication skills. I've worked as university tour guide, where I utilized my leaderships skills to independently manage tours involving **60 people**. I've additionally worked as a mentor, both for my University and for the Microsoft Student accelerator programme, where I refined my ability to convey technical knowledge effectively.

Finally, as part of my drive to improve, I am **highly receptive to feedback** and always make sure to meaningfully follow through.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering (Honours) in Software Engineering

University of Auckland

2021 - 2024

- GPA: 8.0 (A average)
- Dean's Honours List 2022 Top 5% of Engineering Students
- Dean's Honours List 2021 Top 5% of Engineering Students

Experience

Software Engineer Intern - SMX Email Cyber Security Experts

November 2022 - February 2023

- Worked in a cross-functional team, with a data scientist and a computer science graduate, to make a data analytics platform.
- Ran weekly company-wide demos and incorporated key feedback from executives.
- Utilized React, Typescript and NodeJS on a production level.

Software Development Team - Microsoft Student Accelerator New Zealand

April 2023 - Current

- Led weekly office hours to aid students in completing a full stack web development project.
- Curated a week-long curriculum, used by 150 students, to learn front-end web development.

ECSE Part II Assistance Centre Mentor - The University of Auckland

Feb 2023 - Current

 Provided tutoring to students entering their second year of Electrical, Computer, and Software Engineering.

Technical Skills

JavaScript

 Gained extensive experience in JavaScript throughout my internship. Implemented production level code using the language, and related frameworks (Typescript, React, NodeJS)

Java

• Gained experience in Java through objected orientated design for several university projects.

Other languages I have used: Python, C, C++, Lua, VDHL, MATLAB, SQL, SCCharts, AHK

Project Experience

Snake

https://github.com/jxav22/JavaScriptSnake

- A recreation of the classic game of snake
- My focus was on writing highly optimized, modular, and efficient code utilizing my knowledge of OOP, algorithm design and SOLID principles

Portfolio

https://github.com/jxav22/Portfolio

- A portfolio that I created to show off my coding skills.
- Implemented with React, Typescript and NextJS.

Interests

I have a love for drawing and enjoy making digital art. I also play **a lot** of board games; my current favourite is "7 wonders duel".

References

References available on request.